Guide to the Oliver Reiser Papers, 1930-1974 UA.90.F10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Oliver Reiser Papers
1930-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Reiser, Oliver Leslie
UA.90.F10
17 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
Oliver Reiser was an Emeritus Professor of Philosophy at the University of Pittsburgh (1924-1966). His research and teaching interests included the philosophy of science, knowledge integration, general semantics, the philosophy of education, the history of philosophy, religion, and world peace. The materials in this collection include almost four decades of personal and professional correspondence, articles, manuscripts, notes, course documents, and personal papers.
Biography
Oliver Reiser was a self-described cosmic humanist and taught philosophy at the University of Pittsburgh from 1924-1966. He was born in Columbus, Ohio, in 1896 and died on June 6, 1974 at his home in Pittsburgh's Mount Washington neighborhood. He was 78 years old. Reiser served in the U.S. medical corps in France and Belgium in 1917 and 1918. He held B.A., M.A., and Ph.D. degrees in philosophy from Ohio State University, where he finished his graduate work in 1924. Between 1924 and 1926, he did post-doctoral work at the University of Chicago. He joined Pitt's Department of Philosophy in 1926 and retired in 1966. He was Chairman of the Department from 1955-1960. Following his retirement, Reiser stayed on at the university to counsel and teach occasional courses in the philosophy of religion. He was involved in many organizations over the course of his life, including The International Committee on Scientific Humanism, The Council for the Study of Mankind, The American Association for the Advancement of Science, The International Institute of Integrative Studies, the World Futurist Society, and Darshana International.
One of Reiser's former students wrote of him that "in his writing the intention was no less than to combine all knowledge into coherence." All of Reiser's research, teaching, and advocacy centered on this integrative project, as it was his view that rifts were growing in both academia and the larger world. Reiser's best known books included World Philosophy: A Search for Synthesis (University of Pittsburgh Press, 1948), The Integration of Human Knowledge (Porter Sargent, 1958), and Cosmic Humanism (Shenkman Publishing Company). In these works, he attempted to show that scholarly practice within the humanities, the natural sciences, and the social sciences could be understood as a unified inquiry into physical and human nature. He believed this insight when developed would revitalize academia and, ultimately, promote harmonious international relations. While he termed this worldview scientific humanism in his early work, he later preferred the term cosmic humanism. He wrote the following of this attitude toward life: "[scientific humanism] is 'scientific' without being materialistic… it represents idealism without supernaturalism." Reiser worked to establish scholarly relationships with likeminded peers, including Julian Huxley, Alfred Korzybiski, Dane Rudhyar, Blodwen Davies, and Esther Watson-Tipple. His other notable correspondents included Albert Einstein, Arthur C. Clarke, Isaac Asimov, Susanne Langer, Marshal McLuhan, Gaston Bachelard, Edgar Mitchell, and S.I. Hayakawa.
Scope and Content Notes
The Oliver Reiser Papers comprise a wide variety of materials dating from shortly after Reiser's completion of his Ph.D. to shortly before his death in 1974. Reiser's correspondence reflects his many intellectual interests and his commitment to interdisciplinarity. The publications series contains only a portion of his published work, but the annotated drafts and diagrams therein provide valuable insight into Reiser's writing and revision process. The Personal Papers series and Media series contain many materials unique to this collection, including Reiser's handwritten notes on disparate subjects, his thematically organized folders of scientific and philosophical literature, and his awards and clippings. Key themes include the following: general semantics, the integration of knowledge, the history of philosophy, the philosophy of education, the philosophy of mind, world peace, and world religion.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Oliver Reiser Papers, 1930-1974, UA.90.F10, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Deposited in the University Archives in 1979 or 1980.
Arrangement
The Oliver Reiser Papers contain four series:
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Publications
Series III. Personal Papers
Series IV. Media
University of Pittsburgh; Humanists -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Personal papers; Correspondence; Manuscripts for publication; Interdisciplinary approach in education; Interdisciplinary approach to knowledge; Humanism; Science -- Philosophy; General semantics; Integration (Theory of knowledge); Philosophy -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Cosmology; Philosophy; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty; Tipple, Esther Watson; Davies, Blodwen; Reiser, Oliver Leslie
- Correspondence, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Correspondence series is organized alphabetically but contains the following three types of material:
  Persons - personal letters and scholarly conversation. Filed under last name of correspondent.
  Institutions - letters requesting endorsement or nomination, or relating to arrangements for conferences; notices of nominations or of the creation of organizations; descriptions of political programs and proposals; and letters concerning administrative matters.
  Subjects - typically responses to Reiser's publications, which are filed under 'Response to...' Others concern ideas Reiser had that he shared with many correspondents, e.g. 'Concerning a Proposed Institute of Cultural Collaboration.'
  - Abel, Walter (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accra Assembly, The (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ackerman, Iseley, Roberts (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ackerman, Max (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aldrich, Virgil C. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allan, Mary E. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allegro, John (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American College of Hospital Administrators (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Humanist Association (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Humanities Seminar (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Society for Psychical Research, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Amstutz, Jacob (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Andrieu, Pierre (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political & Social Science, The (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arasteh, Reza (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arguelles, Jose A. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aronson, Moses J. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Asana, J.J. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Asimov, Isaac (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Asrani, U.A. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Assagiolo, Robert (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Association for Human Emergence (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Association Internationale Pour Le Developpement De L'Universite Mondiale (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Avery, K. William (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Avey, A.E. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Babcock, Winifred (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bachelard, Gaston (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bailey, Mary (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Barrie, Michael (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Barron, Patricia (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bartley, S. Howard (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Batten, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baugh, R.H. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Beal, James B. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bearden, Thomas E. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Becker, Ernst (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Beischer, D.E. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bennett, John G. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Beorse, Bryn (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Berle, Adolf A. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bernstein, Norman (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Best, James S. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bevis, Howard L. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Biederman, Charles (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Biosophical Institute, The (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bird, Christopher (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Biser, Irwin (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bjørset, Brynjolf (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bliss, C.K. (1) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bliss, C.K. (2) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bliss, C.K. (3) (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bliss, C.K. (4) (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bliss, Henry E. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Bloomstone, Instone (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Boas, George (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Bogardus, Emory S. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bogart, Willard Van de (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Bond, Susan (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Boodin, John E. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Boone, Ilsley (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Boyle, John P. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Bragdon, Claude (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Braham, Mark (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Brahm, Archie J. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Braithaite, R.B. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Brameld, Theodore (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Brancatisano, Fortunato (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Brown, Frank A. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Bunch, Jesse (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Bunzel, Joseph H. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Burnside, Brooks (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Burt, David (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Burtt, Ned (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Buschman, Harold (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Caine, Mary (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Caldwell, Oliver J. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - California Institute of Asian Studies (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Campa, Riccardo (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Campbell, John W. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Carley, James P. (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Castell, Alburey (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Castetter, L.L. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Cayce, Hugh Lynn (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Center for International Studies (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Chan, Wing-tsit (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Chevalier, A. (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Child, C.M. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Clarin, Anders (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Clark, Robert A. (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Clarke, Arthur C. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Cochran, A.A. (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Cofman, Lucy (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Cofman, Victor & de Chardin, Teilhard (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Cole, Francis E. (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Committee for the Future, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Committee on Integration of the Sciences and Humanities (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Committee on Science & Freedom (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Conger, George Perrigo (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Conniff, William J. (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Cooperators (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Council for the Study of Mankind (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Council on International Communications (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Crain, Roy A. (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Creative Age Press, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Crook, F. (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Custard, Harry L. (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Daniels, James L. (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Darling, Charles M. (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Darshana (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Davies, Blodwen (1) (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Davies, Blodwen (2) (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Davies, Blodwen (3) (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Davies, Blodwen (4) (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Davies, Blodwen (5) (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Davies, Blodwen (6) (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Davies, Blodwen (7) (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Davies, Blodwen (8) (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Davis, John W. (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Dawson, Grace S. (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - de Rhoda, Andreas (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Dean, Stanley R. (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Desmonde, William H. (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Dewey, Edward R. (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Dewing (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Diringer, D. (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Dodd, Stuart C. (1) (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Dodd, Stuart C. (2) (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Dodd, Stuart C. (3) (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Drake, Henry L. (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Draper, Glen H. (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Du Noüy, Lecomte (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Ducasse, C.J. (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Dudley, Harold M. (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Dulaney, Richard A. (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Dummer, Ethel (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Dunk, Marion (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Dunn, Halbert L. (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Dunnewolt, Ir. H.W. (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Eckartsberg, Elsa von (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Edson, R.K. (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Education in the New Age preface (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Eisenbud, Jule (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Ellis, Joseph W. (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Encyclopedia of Associations (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Engelson, M. (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Esch, F.W.L. (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Esquire (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Euthanasia Society of America (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Evans, D.L. (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Evanson, Jacob A. (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Everstine, Lovis (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Ewerts, Karl J. (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Fairly, Gene (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Farley, Christopher (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Feinberg, Charles (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Feinberg, Gerald (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Ferguson, Marilyn (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Ferreira, Pinto (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - Fields within Fields (Box 2, Folder 161)
  - First Humanist Society of New York, Inc., The (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - First Unitarian Church of Pittsburgh (Box 2, Folder 163)
  - Fischel, Marguerite K. (Box 2, Folder 164)
  - Floyd, Bill (Box 2, Folder 165)
  - Floyd, Keith (Box 2, Folder 166)
  - Fodor, Nandor (Box 2, Folder 167)
  - Foundation of Thanatology, The (Box 2, Folder 168)
  - Friedrich, Carl J. (Box 2, Folder 169)
  - Frontiers of Science Fellowship (Box 2, Folder 170)
  - Frost, Corinne (Box 2, Folder 171)
  - Fulbright, J.W. (Box 2, Folder 172)
  - Fund for the Behavioral Sciences, The (Box 2, Folder 173)
  - Gammon, Roland (Box 2, Folder 174)
  - Gardner, Richard N. (Box 2, Folder 175)
  - Gibbs, Frederic A. (Box 2, Folder 176)
  - Glastonbury England Circles (Box 2, Folder 177)
  - Gluck Foundation (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Gluck, Arthur (Box 2, Folder 179)
  - Gluck, Samuel E. (Box 2, Folder 180)
  - Goble, Frank (Box 2, Folder 181)
  - Gordon-Brown, Ian (Box 2, Folder 182)
  - Graf, E.R. (Box 2, Folder 183)
  - Griggs, Robert F. (Box 2, Folder 184)
  - Guha, Shrimati Mira (Box 2, Folder 185)
  - Guild of American Economists (Box 2, Folder 186)
  - Gunther, Gotthard (Box 2, Folder 187)
  - Guru, Nataraja (Box 2, Folder 188)
  - Hall, Grover C. (Box 2, Folder 189)
  - Haring-Hillen, E. (Box 2, Folder 190)
  - Harman, Willis W. (Box 2, Folder 191)
  - Hart, Hornell (Box 2, Folder 192)
  - Harten, Marjorie von (Box 2, Folder 193)
  - Hartshorne, Charles (Box 2, Folder 194)
  - Hawkins, Gerald S. (Box 2, Folder 195)
  - Hayakawa, S.I. (Box 2, Folder 196)
  - Heard, Gerald (Box 2, Folder 197)
  - Heason, H.W. (Box 2, Folder 198)
  - Heighton, Henry H. (Box 2, Folder 199)
  - Heleus Michael C. (Box 2, Folder 200)
  - Helson, Harry (Box 2, Folder 201)
  - Henderson, Archibald (Box 2, Folder 202)
  - Herrick, C. Judson (Box 2, Folder 203)
  - Hershey, John H. (Box 2, Folder 204)
  - Hieronimus, Robert (Box 2, Folder 205)
  - Hills, Christopher (Box 2, Folder 206)
  - Hilton, Frank (Box 2, Folder 207)
  - Hinsdale Health Museum (Box 2, Folder 208)
  - Hoagland, Hudson (Box 2, Folder 209)
  - Hodgson, Anthony M. (Box 2, Folder 210)
  - Holther, William B. (Box 2, Folder 211)
  - Hovde, Bryn J. (Box 2, Folder 212)
  - Hubbard, Barbara (Box 2, Folder 213)
  - Hullfish, H. Gordon (Box 2, Folder 214)
  - Humanist (Box 2, Folder 215)
  - Humanist Press Association (Box 2, Folder 216)
  - Huxley, Julian (Box 3, Folder 217)
  - Institute for Philosophy, Psychology, and Psychical Research (Box 3, Folder 218)
  - Institute for Semantography (Box 3, Folder 219)
  - Institute for the Comparative Study of History, Philosophy and Science (Box 3, Folder 220)
  - Institute of General Semantics (Box 3, Folder 221)
  - Institute of Human Fellowship (Box 3, Folder 222)
  - Institute of Noetic Sciences, The (Box 3, Folder 223)
  - Intelligence: The Mensa Journal (Box 3, Folder 224)
  - International Center for Integrative Studies (Box 3, Folder 225)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnographical Sciences (Box 3, Folder 226)
  - International Cooperation Institute (Box 3, Folder 227)
  - International Council for Philosophy and Humanistic Studies (Box 3, Folder 228)
  - International Research Center for Mathematics, Morphology, Morphogenesis (Box 3, Folder 229)
  - International Society for General Semantics (Box 3, Folder 230)
  - International Symposium on the Science of Creative Intelligence (Box 3, Folder 231)
  - Jelliffe, Smith Ely (Box 3, Folder 232)
  - Jennings, Florence (Box 3, Folder 233)
  - Jöel, Walther (Box 3, Folder 234)
  - John U. and Evelyn Nef Foundation (Box 3, Folder 235)
  - Johnson, H.M. (Box 3, Folder 236)
  - Johnson, Jerry L. (Box 3, Folder 237)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 3, Folder 238)
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, The (Box 3, Folder 239)
  - Journal of Parapsychology (Box 3, Folder 240)
  - Junek, Oscar Waldemar (Box 3, Folder 241)
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 3, Folder 242)
  - Kandel, I.L. (Box 3, Folder 243)
  - Kattsoff, Louis O. (Box 3, Folder 244)
  - Kendig, Marjorie (Box 3, Folder 245)
  - Keyser, C.J. (Box 3, Folder 246)
  - Kicken, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 247)
  - King, C.G. (Box 3, Folder 248)
  - Kingston, M.S. (Box 3, Folder 249)
  - Kirk, John R. (Box 3, Folder 250)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde (Box 3, Folder 251)
  - Koffka, Kurt (Box 3, Folder 252)
  - Korzybski, Alfred (Box 3, Folder 253)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard (Box 3, Folder 254)
  - Kundulini Research Foundation (Box 3, Folder 255)
  - Kunz, F.L. (Box 3, Folder 256)
  - Kurtz, Paul (Box 3, Folder 257)
  - Ladd-Franklin, Christine (Box 3, Folder 258)
  - Lamont, Corliss (Box 3, Folder 259)
  - Land, George T. (Box 3, Folder 260)
  - Langer, Susanne K. (Box 3, Folder 261)
  - Larson, Arthur (Box 3, Folder 262)
  - Laszlo, Ervin (Box 3, Folder 263)
  - Laucks, Irving F. (Box 3, Folder 264)
  - Leader, Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 265)
  - Leake, Chauncey D. (Box 3, Folder 266)
  - Lee, Irving J. (Box 3, Folder 267)
  - Lee, Jung Young (Box 3, Folder 268)
  - Leek, Sybil (Box 3, Folder 269)
  - Lewis, Gilbert N. (Box 3, Folder 270)
  - Lewis, Samuel L. (Box 3, Folder 271)
  - Lins, Mario (Box 3, Folder 272)
  - London, Ivan D. (Box 3, Folder 273)
  - Longenecker, Herber H. (Box 3, Folder 274)
  - Lorbeen, Floyd I. (Box 3, Folder 275)
  - Loring, Ruth (Box 3, Folder 276)
  - Loring, Ruth, 1970-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - Lotka, Alfred J. (Box 3, Folder 277)
  - Loverde, Dorin (Box 3, Folder 278)
  - Lowinger, Armand (Box 3, Folder 279)
  - Luce, Henry R. (Box 3, Folder 280)
  - Lundberg, George A. (Box 3, Folder 281)
  - Lyle, Joseph D. (Box 3, Folder 282)
  - Malisoff, William M. (Box 3, Folder 283)
  - Mann, Edward W. (Box 3, Folder 284)
  - Man's Nature and Spirit Panel (Box 3, Folder 285)
  - Marois, M. (Box 3, Folder 286)
  - Martin, William W. (Box 3, Folder 287)
  - Mason, E.R., Jr. (Box 3, Folder 288)
  - Maxey, E. Stanton (Box 3, Folder 289)
  - May, Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 290)
  - Mayne, Alan (Box 3, Folder 291)
  - McDonald, Arthur G. (Box 3, Folder 292)
  - McLain, Paul L. (Box 3, Folder 293)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 3, Folder 294)
  - Medlock, Julie (Box 3, Folder 295)
  - Metcalfe, Ernest (Box 3, Folder 296)
  - Michell, John (Box 3, Folder 297)
  - Missing or illegible signature (1) (Box 3, Folder 298)
  - Missing or illegible signature (2) (Box 3, Folder 299)
  - Mitchell Press Limited (Box 3, Folder 300)
  - Mitchell, Edgar D. (Box 3, Folder 301)
  - Mitchell, William M. (Box 3, Folder 302)
  - Modley, Rudolf (Box 3, Folder 303)
  - Montagu, Ashley (Box 3, Folder 304)
  - Montague, William Pepperell (Box 3, Folder 305)
  - Moor, Arthur P. (Box 3, Folder 306)
  - Moore, Hugh (Box 3, Folder 307)
  - Moorhead, William S. (Box 3, Folder 308)
  - Morain, Lloyd (Box 3, Folder 309)
  - Morris, Robert L. (Box 3, Folder 310)
  - Mott, Francis J. (Box 3, Folder 311)
  - Multicom Corps (Box 3, Folder 312)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 3, Folder 313)
  - Murphy, Gardner (Box 3, Folder 314)
  - Murray, Elwood (Box 3, Folder 315)
  - Naturaja, Guru (Box 3, Folder 316)
  - Northrop, F.S.C. (Box 3, Folder 317)
  - Nostrand, Howard Lee (Box 3, Folder 318)
  - Nye, L.J.J. (Box 3, Folder 319)
  - O'Loughlin, Charles F. (Box 3, Folder 320)
  - O'Regan, Brendan (Box 3, Folder 321)
  - Parker, George F. (Box 3, Folder 322)
  - Peace Circle of the Students of Philosophy of Humboldt University (Box 3, Folder 323)
  - Peake, Charles H. (Box 3, Folder 324)
  - Peerbolte, M. Lietaert (Box 3, Folder 325)
  - Philosopher's Index, The (Box 3, Folder 326)
  - Philosophy Forum, The (Box 3, Folder 327)
  - Philosophy of Science Association (Box 3, Folder 328)
  - Phoenix Institute, The (Box 3, Folder 329)
  - Pickler, Andrew G. (Box 3, Folder 330)
  - Pierce, Anne (Box 3, Folder 331)
  - Piper, Raymond F. (Box 3, Folder 332)
  - Plummer, Howard (Box 3, Folder 333)
  - Polakov, Walter N. (Box 3, Folder 334)
  - Pontzen, Theodore C. (Box 3, Folder 335)
  - Portal (Box 4, Folder 336)
  - Porter Sargent Publisher (Box 4, Folder 337)
  - Potter, Francis Charles (Box 4, Folder 338)
  - Price, H.H. (Box 4, Folder 339)
  - Prince, Raymond (Box 4, Folder 340)
  - Project Prometheus & Krishna Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 341)
  - Psychosynthesis Center (Box 4, Folder 342)
  - Psychosynthesis Research Foundation (Box 4, Folder 343)
  - Puharich, Andrija & Henry K. (Box 4, Folder 344)
  - Rahtz, P.A. (Box 4, Folder 345)
  - Rankin, Alan C. (Box 4, Folder 346)
  - Rashevsky, Nicolas (Box 4, Folder 347)
  - Reinhardt, Louis H. (Box 4, Folder 348)
  - Reps, Paul (Box 4, Folder 349)
  - Response to Alchemy of Light & Color (Box 4, Folder 350)
  - Response to Cosmecology (Box 4, Folder 351)
  - Response to Cosmic Humanism (Box 4, Folder 352)
  - Response to Humanistic Logic for the Mind in Action (Box 4, Folder 353)
  - Response to The Integration of Human Knowledge (Box 4, Folder 354)
  - Response to New Earth and a New Humanity (Box 4, Folder 355)
  - Response to Philosophy and the Concepts of Modern Science (Box 4, Folder 356)
  - Response to July 26, 1963 Pittsburgh Press Letter to the Editor (Box 4, Folder 357)
  - Response to Planetary Democracy (Box 4, Folder 358)
  - Response to The Promise of Scientific Humanism (Box 4, Folder 359)
  - Response to Unified Symbolism for World Understanding in Science (Box 4, Folder 360)
  - Response to The World Sensorium (Box 4, Folder 361)
  - Rhine, J.B. (1) (Box 4, Folder 362)
  - Rhine, J.B. (2) (Box 4, Folder 363)
  - Rice, C. Hilton (Box 4, Folder 364)
  - Richards, Harriet (Box 4, Folder 365)
  - Richardson, David B. (Box 4, Folder 366)
  - Roberts, Gordon J. (Box 4, Folder 367)
  - Robertson, H.P. (Box 4, Folder 368)
  - Robinson, Catherine Adair (Box 4, Folder 369)
  - Rockwell Jr., W.F. (Box 4, Folder 370)
  - Royce, Joseph R. (Box 4, Folder 371)
  - Rudhyar, Dane (Box 4, Folder 372)
  - Safranek, Milos (Box 4, Folder 373)
  - Sandage, Allan (Box 4, Folder 374)
  - Santelli, Em Cesar (Box 4, Folder 375)
  - Schlegel, Richard (Box 4, Folder 376)
  - Schmitt, Mary F. (Box 4, Folder 377)
  - Schochen, Seyril (Box 4, Folder 378)
  - School for Biospherical Peace Research Within Man (Box 4, Folder 379)
  - Schwartz, Jack (Box 4, Folder 380)
  - Scientia (Box 4, Folder 381)
  - Seubert, Eugene E. (Box 4, Folder 382)
  - Shambala Publications Inc. (Box 4, Folder 383)
  - Shapley, Harlow (Box 4, Folder 384)
  - Shefler, Oscar (Box 4, Folder 385)
  - Sheldon, Wilman H. (Box 4, Folder 386)
  - Silver, A.L. Leigh (Box 4, Folder 387)
  - Simeon, John (Box 4, Folder 388)
  - Sinkiewicz, John T. (Box 4, Folder 389)
  - Sir George Williams University (Box 4, Folder 390)
  - Skornia, Harry J. (Box 4, Folder 391)
  - Sleyub, Scott (Box 4, Folder 392)
  - Smith, J. Holmes (Box 4, Folder 393)
  - Smith III, Robert A. (Box 4, Folder 394)
  - Smyser, Selden (Box 4, Folder 395)
  - Society for Freedom in Science (Box 4, Folder 396)
  - Society for the Investigation of the Unexplained (Box 4, Folder 397)
  - Somerville, John (Box 4, Folder 398)
  - Southern Connectitut State College Center for Interdisciplinary Creativity (Box 4, Folder 399)
  - Speedie, Gordon (1) (Box 4, Folder 400)
  - Speedie, Gordon (2) (Box 4, Folder 401)